Guide to the Thomas Fry Tobey Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Military Papers, 1862-1920; Series II; 0.5; (1 box)
  - Appointment: Charles B. Kerney, Second Lieutenant, Porto Rico Provisional Regiment, 1901 Jul 1
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 183
  - Appointment: Charles B. Kerney, Captain, Porto Rico Provisional Regiment, 1902 Mar 20
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 184
  - Appointment: Major, retired, 1904 Apre 23
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folders 185-86
  - Correspondence, 1920, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Records of military service, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Family Papers, 1845-1929; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  The papers is Series III are alphabetically arranged by name of individual and then by type of material.
  - Miller, Christopher
    - Estate papers, 1875-79 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Tobey family
    - Genealogical information, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Tobey, John Fry
    - Notebook, 1853-54 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Memorial tribute by the Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Tobey, Mary Rebecca Wingaard
    - Invitations, 1897-1929 (Box 3, Folder 89-91)
  - Tobey, Samuel Boyd
    - Biographical information, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Obituary, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Resolution: Board of Managers of the Home for Aged Women, [1867?] (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Tobey, Sarah Fry
    - Memorial cards, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Tobey, Thomas Fry
    - Baptism, certification of, 1920 May 22 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Certificate: excellence in Latin, Brown University, 1857 Sep 2
      See: Oversize: Box 10, folder 187
    - Diary, 1868-69 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Diary, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Diary, 1885-86 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Diploma: Brown University, M.A., 1859 Sep 7
      See: Oversize: Box 10, folder 188
    - Diploma: Harvard University, LL.B., 1861 Jul 17
      See: Oversize: Box 10, folder 189
    - Invitations, 1898-1917, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 100-08)
    - Memorabilia
      - Belt buckles, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 109-11)
      - Hair, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 112)
      - Pipe smoked at Battle of Fredericksburg, December 13, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 113)
      - Ribbon, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - Uniform braid, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 115-16)
      - Wooden plaque, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Notes on 7th Rhode Island Volunteers and the Battle of Fredericksburg (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Notes on 10th Rhode Island Volunteers (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Obituary, 1920 Jun 16 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Reminiscences, 1897-98 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - "Statements in Reference to the Last Days of Crazy Horse, Taken from the Crawford, Neb. Tribune, June 26, 1903: typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 123)
- Photographs, 1851-1874; Series IV; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs, consists of two boxes of alphabetically arranged photographs, daguerreotypes, stereographs, and tintypes.
  - Comstock, Elizabeth L., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - "T.E. Barnhouse, Lake City, Colo.": stereograph, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Tobey family: daguerreotype, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Tobey family: stereographs, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - Tobey, Mary Rebecca Wingaard and Marie Tobey on her wedding day (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Tobey, Sarah Fry, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 129-30)
  - Tobey, Thomas Fry: daguerreotype, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Tobey, Thomas Fry: tintype, 1862 Jun 23 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Tobey, Thomas Fry, 1859-62, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Tobey, William, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - "Walloper": dog belonging to Thomas Fry Tobey, 1874 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Unidentified woman: daguerreotype (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Unidentified individuals (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Tintype case: empty, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 138)
- Writings, 1844-88; Series V; 0.25; (1 box)
  The papers in Writings are alphabetically arranged by author and title.
  - Ohnet, Georges
    - "The Kleptomaniac. A Banker's Story": English translation from the French, holograph in hand of Thomas Fry Tobey (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Tobey, Thomas Fry
    - "Academic Loyalty": holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "The American Captains": holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - "At Nashville": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - "Cleaning Out a Guard-house": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - "The Colonel of the Prisoners": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 144-45)
    - "The Colonel's Story": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - "The Compulsory education of enlisted men in post schools": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - "The decline of imagination in old age": holograph, 1859 Jul 5 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - "The Enlisted Man": holograph, incomplete, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - Exercises 77th, 78th, and 79th: holograph (in Latin) with corrections, 1855 (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - "For a Woman": holograph, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - "How the Irish do it": holograph, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - "How we were counselled to capture Carthagena": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - "Lecture on Battle of Bunker Hill": holograph, corrected, 1888 (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - "Lecture (Operations following Bunker Hill)": holograph, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - "Maricopa Traditions": holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - "The Meeting in the 77th": holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - "My First Story Book": holograph, 1844 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - "My General": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - "The 77th and its Meeting": holograph, corrected (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - "The Story of a battalion": holograph, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - "A Tight Place": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - "Who was Hi Jolly?": holograph, incomplete, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Untitled writing fragments: holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Waterman, Marcus
    - "The Legend of Conydon's Cave. A Tale of Conanicut": copied by John Fry Tobey, holograph, 1855 Aug 25 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Unidentified author
    - Untitled poem: holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 166)
- Printed Works, 1808-1879; Series VI; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  - Aide-Mémoire ou Tableaux Synoptiques, ..., 7th edition, 1858 (Box 8, Folder 166a)
  - Daily Richmond Whig.: newspaper
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 190
  - De Bow's Review: inscribed, "John F. Tobey with love of Capt. T. F. T. Picked up in Fredericksburg, Va. the day we occupied it. Dec. 12th, 1862", 1862 Jan-Feb (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - The Epistle from the Yearly Meeting, Held in London, 1808 May (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Freedom: The Giant of the Orient: newspaper
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 191
  - General Orders Affecting the Volunteer Force, 1862 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Gilbert, Rev. D. The Love of Jesus; or, Visits to the Blessed Sacrament ,..., 1873 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Horae Diurnae: Breviarii Romani ,..., signed by Thomas F. Tobey May 1865, 1857 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Mr. Webster's Speech in Defence of the Christian Ministry ...: inscribed, "For Mr. Tobey from his friend J. B. Francis", 1844 Apr (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - The Providence Daily Journal: newspaper
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 192
  - The Providence Journal: newspaper
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 193
  - Report of the Trustees of the Rhode Island Hospital, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 173)
  - San Francisco Chronicle: newspaper
    See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 194
  - Trial of George Crowninshield, J. J. Knapp, Jun. and John Francis Knapp, for the Murder of Joseph White, of Salem ..., 1830 (Box 9, Folder 174)
  - The United Service. A Quarterly Review of Military and Navel Affairs, 1879 Jan (Box 9, Folder 175)
- Oversize, 1857-1920; 2; (1 box)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series II, III, and VI.
  - MILITARY PAPERS
    - Appointment: Sergeant, 10th Rhode Island Volunteers, 1862 May 26 (Box 10, Folder 176)
    - Appointment: Major, 7th Rhode Island Volunteers, 1863 Feb 7 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - Appointment: Second Lieutenant, 14th Infantry, 1866 Apr 23 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Appointment: First Lieutenant, 14th Infantry, 1866 Apr 20 (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Appointment: Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1869 Apr 6 (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Appointment: Captain, 14th Infantry, 1875 Jan 5 (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Certificate: Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1880 Jan 7 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Appointment: Charles B. Kerney, Second Lieutenant, Porto Rico Privisional Regiment, 1901 Jul 1 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Appointment: Charles B. Kerney, Captain, Porto Rico Provisional Regiment, 1902 Mar 20 (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - Appointment: Major, retired, 1904, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 185-86)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - Certificate: Latin, Brown University, 1857 Sep 2 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Diploma: M.A., Brown Unversity, 1859 Sep 7 (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - Diploma: LL.B., Harvard College, 1861 Jul 17 (Box 10, Folder 189)
  - PRINTED WORKS
    - Daily Richmond Whig, 1862 Feb 21 (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - Freedom: The Giant of the Orient, 1899 May 7 (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - The Providence Daily Journal, 1915 Jan 9 (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - The Providence Journal, 1920 Jun 16 (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, 1898 Jun 5 (Box 10, Folder 194)